SHANE ABRAHAM

Waterloo, ON, Canada | shaneabh777@gmail.com | +1 548 384 2237 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

Professional Profile

Enthusiastic software developer at Conestoga College with proficiency in C, C++, Java, and Python. Recognized with a golden visa for academic excellence. Experienced in project management methodologies, with strong problem-solving skills and a commitment to delivering high-quality results in web development.

Education

Conestoga College Waterloo (2023-2024)

Web Development

- Collaborating effectively within a team to successfully deliver projects.
- Developing proficiency in web development techniques and technologies.
- Acquiring knowledge in business analytics and understanding customer requirements.

Middlesex University Dubai (2019-2022)

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

- First-class honors (4.0 GPA)
- Demonstrated strong leadership and teamwork skills through diverse group projects.
- Familiarity with both waterfall and agile project management methodologies.

Experience

ePROMIS Solutions LLC, Dubai

Aug 2022 – Oct 2022

Software Tester

- Worked with content to improve the reach of the company through different social media platforms.
- Queried data from SQL and performed data analysis.
- Designed websites using JavaScript, HTML, and tailwind.
- Worked with senior staff to understand the workflow process of the organization.

Fly Dubai Nov 2022 – Feb 2023

Software Developer Intern

- Acquired knowledge and expertise in software development best practices and coding standards.
- Developed a REST API using a structured spring boot application and gained experience in API request interception to check headers.
- · Practiced performing CRUD operations in MongoDB and implementing Redis-based commands.
- Utilized MongoDB as a cache to improve application performance.
- Extracted and transferred code from a big project to a new project, and exposed the information collected from the database as an API.
- Acquired the ability to create and document APIs, including understanding Lombok and creating technical documentation.
- Expanded skillset by learning Flutter to add additional UI features to a Big Data dashboard.

SHANE ABRAHAM

Waterloo, ON, Canada | shaneabh777@gmail.com | +1 548 384 2237 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Website

Professional skills

- Python, Java, C++, Django, Flask, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL, NoSQL, React JS, Stimulsoft.
- Strong leadership, communication, and collaboration skills
- Fluent in reading, writing, and speaking English.
- Skilled in advanced critical thinking, problem-solving, and logic.
- Capable of developing and explain ideas and methods clearly.
- Proficient in MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, and MS word.
- Ability to multitask and work in fast-paced environments.